Shao-Chun Ma

Software Engineer

J (+49) 1525-8706794 • 13581, Berlin, Germany justwhenithought@gmail.com https://github.com/cand126 in https://www.linkedin.com/in/shao-chun-ma

Profile

A Java/Kotlin developer with 5 years experience in backend development, based in Berlin. Have permanent EU residence permit. Work with Kotlin, Spring Boot, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL on microservice architecture. Have deployment experience on Kubernetes and AWS. Prefer clean code and complete monitoring system.

Employment History

03.2020 - Now	Software Engineer at SHARE NOW	Berlin
	 Implemented microservices with Kotlin, Java 17, Spring, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL and MongoDB Built simple frontend applications with TypeScript and Vue 2 Migrated Kubernetes services and databases from IBM Clould to AWS Analysed and monitored services with ELK, New Relic, Sentry, Prometheus, and Grafana Improved CI/CD pipelines in Gitlab, including Helm charts Defined SLOs and alerting rules, and envolved in the on-call schedule Participated in long-term car sharing in a Scrum team 	
08.2018 - 02.2020	Junior Fall-Stack Engineer at omni:us	Berlin
	 Developed microservices with Java 8+, Spring, Python 3, Flask Built data pipelines with Apache Airflow Helped data scientists to maintain and deploy Al microservices Managed PostgreSQL databases with SQLAlchemy Extracted data from XML format to JSON format with Java Provided a research proposal about Apache Kafka Deployed Docker images with Kubernetes and Helm Charts Automated CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins 	
02.2017 - 12.2017	Web Developer (Student Job) at Lyrehouse	Aachen
	 Contributed to WordPress projects with PHP, MySQL, and Docker Improved the project by refactoring into MVC architecture Involved in weekly Agile meetings Completed several reusable components 	
Education		

09.2016 - 07.2018	RWTH Aachen University	Aachen
	Master of Science, Software Systems Engineering	
09.2011 - 06.2015	National Taiwan University	Taipei, Taiwan
	Bachelor of Business Administration, Information Management	

Skills

Kotlin, Java, Spring Boot, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Kubernetes, Sentry, ELK, New Relic, JavaScript, Vue

Languages

English, German, Chinese, Japanese